

■ kingab\_93@yahoo.com @adammking **4** 3617906185

**♀** Austin. TX

in adammking adammking

# **SUMMARY**

Full-stack software engineer with experience building applications from development to deployment. Demonstrated experience designing database schemas, constructing RESTful API endpoints, and creating user-friendly interfaces with various technology stacks. Versatile professional with over seven years of experience working in fast-paced environments, de-escalating high-stress situations, and managing mental health crises.

# **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: Python, Javascript, SQL, CSS, HTML

FRAMEWORKS AND LIBRARIES: Express.js, Node.js, Flask, JQuery, Jasmine, Jest, Bootstrap, Python Unit Test, React, Redux, Redux-persist TOOLS: Git, Postgresql, Axios, Flask-WTForms, Flask-SQLAlchemy, Jinja, VSCode, Heroku, Surge

### **PROJECTS**

Feb. 2021 to Mar. 2021 **BEERVANA WEB APP** 

Full-stack application of a social media website for craft beer lovers.

http://beervana.surge.sh/

- Designed database schemas with Postgresql

- Created back end RESTful API with Node.js and Express
- Constructed user-friendly front-end with React and Redux
- Utilized authentication through JWT's
- Deployed back end through Heroku and Front End through Surge

**JOBLY APP** Dec. 2020 to Jan. 2021

Full-stack application of a mock job board with companies and job postings.

http://jobly-front.surge.sh/

- Created fully functional back end with Node.js and Express.js
- Designed front end functionality with React.js
- Utilized authentication through JWT's
- Deployed back end through Heroku and Front End through Surge

Aug. 2020 to Sept. 2020 **HELPER APP** 

A full-stack application that provides support and resources for individuals suffering from depression.

https://capstoneone.herokuapp.com/

- Designed database schemas using Postgresql
- Created RESTful web routes using Python and Flask
- Utilized three separate API'S using Javascript
- Styled design of frontend using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap

### **EDUCATION**

# **Springboard Software Engineering Career Track**

Certification 2020

9-month intensive course in Software Engineering methodologies and technologies

Texas A&M University at Corpus Christi

M.S. Clinical Mental Health Counseling 2018

University of Texas at Austin Aug. 2011 to May 2015

B.A. Philosophy 2015

### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### **AVAIL SOLUTIONS INC.**

Corpus Christi Crisis Worker Sept. 2018 to Dec. 2020

- Provided crisis intervention for individuals experiencing suicidal or homicidal thoughts, or who were actively hallucinating
- Cooperated with multiple agencies (Police/Sheriff's Departments, Hospitals, Jails) to ensure clients mental health and safety needs were met

H-E-B GROCERY COMPANY

**Various Locations** June 2010 to Dec. 2017

Apr. 2020 to Current

Jan. 2016 to Aug. 2018

**Various Positions**